hobnox.com 2008-09-13

# Hobnox - Privacy Policy

The protection of your personal data is very important to us. We commit ourselves to handling your personal data with great care and only in compliance with legal requirements. The following privacy policy will give you an overview on how we garantee this protection and what type of data is collected for what purpose.

### Server Logs

When you visit or use our websites, we automatically collect and save technical information that is transmitted by your browser in server-logs. In particular, this is time of server request, IP address, referrer URL (previously visited page), browser-type and -version, operating system, called up page/content incl. duration of visit and country of origin (as far as detectable). We are not able to allocate these information to your person, since there is no consolidation with other sources of information. 

### Cookies

Our websites use so called cookies to make our services safer, more usable and more effective. Cookies are small text files that are saved on your computer by your browser. Most of the cookies we use are so called "session cookies", which are deleted automatically once your usage is finished. In addition, Hobnox utilizes anonymous information regarding the use of its websites in order to evaluate, improve and market its products. This information does not allow any inference on individual users. Cookies are not able to harm your computer. In case that cookies on your computer are not being deleted directly after usage, you are able to delete them manually at any time. You may also deactivate the usage of cookies by configuring your browser settings. Further information can be found in the help function of your browser. All of our services can of course be used without cookies.

### Newsletter

You are invited to subscribe to our interesting newsletters. In this process we verify the correctness of your email-address and your consent by employing the so called "double opt-in" procedure. This means that your newsletter subscription has to be confirmed in a second step by clicking on a confirmation link which is sent by email to the entered email-address. This deters others from subscribing you to our services without your consent. We do not collect further information in this context. You may revoke your consent at any time by unsubscribing. Each newsletter contains an individualised unsubscription-link. You may also send your revocation to privacy(a)hobnox.com.

### Registered users

If you use our services as a registered user, we collect, save and use basic personal information (first name, last name, address and other comparable data) as well as further voluntary information. All information is handled with great care and is only used for purposes of contractual fulfillment. Your personal data will never be issued to third parties without your explicit consent. We reserve the right to verify your entered registration data by reconciling with other sources.

We collect, save and use your data to the extent that t is needed for contractual fullfilment. We delete user data as long as it is not needed for billing purposes or you have not agreed to its storage and usage.

### Right of information, further information

You may request information about your saved personal data, its origin and recipients as well as the purpose of the storage. In case you have further or more detailed questions, feel free to send an email to our data protection officer (privacy(a)hobnox.com).

_As of: October 2007_
